Guide to the Kent State Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Kent State collection
1967-2017
1970-1985
MS 804
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
74.38
Model: 50 cubic feet
The collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts drafts, legal papers, clippings, issues of the Daily Kent Stater, interview transcripts, photographs and other material collected by Peter Davies, Paul Keane, Bill Gordon, James Munves and others concerning the disturbance at Kent State University and the shooting of Kent State students by members of the Ohio National Guard on May 4, 1970. The collection also includes a model of the Kent State campus.
Kent State University
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gifts of Peter Davies, Michael Astrue, Lesley Wischmann, Paul Keane, Bill Gordon, James Munves, and others, 1976-1994, 1997. Gift of Paul Keane, 2009, 2010 and 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
Series I, Box 25 is closed due to court order.
Researchers must have written permission from Bill Gordon to use his correspondence in Series III, Box 4.
Access to materials in Series II, as well as materials in Accessions 1982-M-016, 1990-M-047, and 2006-M-115 requires the permission of Paul Keane until May 4, 2020.
Access to the model of the Kent State site in Series V requires permission in advance from the Director of Manuscripts and Archives. The model is stored at the off-site Library Shelving Facility in five boxes and measures 50 cubic feet when assembled.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Copies of commercially produced audiovisual materials contained in this collection cannot be made for researcher use outside of the repository.
Accruals
This Kent State Collection is closed for additions of new materials except from those whose papers are already included in the collection. The one exception to this is a promised donation of Sanford J. Rosen's files documenting the civil suit brought by the victims' families against Ohio government officials in United States District Court.
Related Materials
ACLU of Ohio Kent State Project Records (MS 1800). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Existence and Location of Copies
Notebooks of Peter Davies are available on microfilm (2,000 frames on 2 reels, 16mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM119.
Arrangement
Organized in five series and fifteen additions: I. Peter Davies. II. Paul Keane. III. Bill Gordon. IV. James Munves. V. Additional Donors.
Scope and Contents
The Kent State Collection in Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, originated with the efforts of Peter Davies, author of The Truth about Kent State, and his friend Paul Keane to find a safe repository for the material that Mr. Davies had created and collected in the course of his research. The major part of the the papers came to Yale on the seventh anniversary of the May 4, 1970, killings, and the Yale Political Union commemorated that gift by sponsoring a five-day colloquium featuring such civil libertarians as Henry Steele Commager and Aryeh Neier as well as Davies, Keane, and others who had long been studying and protesting what happened at Kent State. Since then the library has endeavored to build on this foundation by collecting other relevant manuscripts, but Davies' papers remain the core of the Collection.
The largest quantity of unique material in the Kent State Collection is Peter Davies' correspondence, beginning with his protest to President Nixon on May 8 and spanning seven strenuous years of inquiry, agitation, and organization. This is, above all, a record of the impact of Kent State on Davies and his correspondents: the parents of the victims, the public officials from whom he demanded an accounting, and the citizens who shared his outrage and collaborated in his protests and probings. The letters document in extraordinary detail the development of Davies' understanding of what happened at Kent State and the progress of his collaborative efforts to obtain redress through public opinion and the legal system. In addition, there are notes, drafts, and unpublished writings that add considerably to the public record of his analysis.
The Kent State Collection also contains a large quantity of research material that would be very useful in a fresh inquiry into Kent State and its aftermath. These are the major kinds of material: two feet of newspaper clippings, spanning from 1970 to 1978; several thousand pages of photostatic copies of F. B. I. Documents, purchased by Yale under the Freedom of Information Act; many publication from Kent State, including newspapers, yearbooks, leaflets, and commemorative booklets; and briefs, transcripts, and other documents related to various legal proceedings. These materials thoroughly document the public perception of Kent State, and give easy access to much information that is otherwise available only in widely scattered sources.
Adapted from The Left Review, "Kent State: Ten Years After," 1980, page 75.
Kent State Shootings, Kent, Ohio, 1970; Riots; Students; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements; United States -- Politics and government; Davies, Peter, 1931-; Gordon, Bill; Keane, Paul; Munves, James, 1922-; Kent State University -- Students
- Peter Davies papers, 1968-1980; Series I
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access Restriction: Trial-relted material in Series I, Box 25 is closed by court order.
  - Correspondence
    - A-Ka [including Davies' carbon copies, filed under his name], 1970-1978 (Box 1)
    - Ke-Z, 1970-1978 (Box 2)
  - Statements and writings about Kent State by Davies and others
    - A-M, 1970-1978 (Box 3)
    - N-Z, 1970-1978 (Box 4)
  - The Truth about Kent State by Peter Davies
    - Drafts and bound proofs, 1971-1974 (Box 5)
    - Unbound proofs, reviews, promotional matter, 1971-1974 (Box 6)
  - Legal papers
    - Pryor v. Davies, 1970-1978 (Box 7)
    - Krause v. Ohio, 1970-1978 (Box 7)
    - Canfora v. Olds, 1970-1978 (Box 7)
    - Krause v. Rhodes
      - U.S. Court of Appeals, 1970-1978 (Box 8)
      - U.S. District and Supreme Courts, 1970-1978 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970-1978 (Box 9)
  - Clippings
    - 1970 (Box 10)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 11)
    - 1973-1974 October (Box 12)
    - 1974 November-1975 (Box 13)
    - 1976-1980, and undated (Box 14)
  - "Minority Report of the Commission on KSU Violence", 1971 (Box 15)
  - President's Commission on Campus Unrest: Kent State hearings and published report, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Books, reprints, and miscellaneous publications, 1970-1975 (Box 16)
  - Daily Kent Stater and American Report, 1972-1977 (Box 17)
  - Photographs, 1970, undated (Box 18)
    - Additional material, 1971-1977 (Box 26)
  - Films and tapes, 1970-1977 (Box 19)
  - Memorabilia of commemorative and protest activities, 1970-1974 (Box 20)
    - Posters, 1971-1977 (Box 26)
  - Interests of Davies other than Kent State
    - Patty Hearst: writings, clippings, 1974-1977 (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous: writings, clippings, 1968-1978 (Box 22)
    - Books on various political subjects, 1970-1975 (Box 23)
  - Notes, documents, personal papers, 1970-1977 (Box 24)
  - Trial-related material, 1970-1977 (Box 25)
    These records are closed by court order.
  - Scrapbook regarding Patty Hearst, Circa 1975 (Box 26)
- Paul Keane papers, 1970-1981, 2001-2006; Series II
  General note
  See also Accessions 1982-M-016, 1990-M-047, and 2006-M-115.
  Access to materials in this series requires the permission of Paul Keane until May 4, 2020.
  - "Kent State: A Ten-Year Ministry", 1980 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Identified by Keane as the key to his papers and recommended as such to all researchers.
  - Kent State/May 4th material
    - American Report, special supplement on Kent State, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Bibliography of Kent State/May 4th, compiled by Reece Morehead, Undated (Box 1)
    - The Contagion of Kent State, by Charles Thomas, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Gym protest, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Leaflets, handouts, literature collected at rallies, 1972, undated (Box 1)
    - Mailing list of colleges for national petition drive, 1971 (Box 1)
    - May 4th memorials and tributes, 1973-1979 (Box 1)
    - Petition to the Federal Grand Jury (Box 1)
      - Pages 1-483, Undated (Box 1)
      - Tabulation of petition drive, Undated (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1972 (Box 1)
      - Newspaper articles, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Petition to the White House (Box 1)
      - "Ten Months of Deceit", 1972 (Box 1)
      - Congressional Record, 1972 (Box 1)
      - Articles and documents resulting from petition drive, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
    - Poetry on Kent State/May 4th, Undated (Box 1)
    - Questionnaire concerning attitudes towards May 4th, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Report of the Kent State Grand Jury, 1972 (Box 1)
    - ROTC protests: news articles, 1970-1972 (Box 1)
    - Saxbe, William: correspondence and related material, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Schroeder v. Bork, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Kent State: May 4, 1970, Synesthetics Inc. film, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of Keane-Rambo interview, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Unsorted material on Kent State: correspondence, clippings, memorandum, printed matter, 1971-1977 (Box 1)
  - Center for Peaceful Change
    - Anatomy of Peaceful Change class (Box 1)
      - Book reviews, 1972 (Box 1)
      - Papers and essays, 1972 (Box 1)
      - Readings and outlines, Undated (Box 1)
      - Roster, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence and articles concerning Granville-Jackson sculpture, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence concerning Hyde Park, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Description and evaluation, Undated (Box 1)
    - Grant proposals, Undated (Box 1)
    - Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Program proposals, purposes, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Proposals for 4 May Research Center, 1973 (Box 1)
    - CPC Class 100: correspondence over permanent memorial, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Continued correspondence over memorial, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Hank Koch article on memorial, Undated (Box 1)
    - Brochure, Undated (Box 1)
  - Kent State F.A.C.T.
    - Address book, Undated (Box 2)
    - Agenda for meeting on 1 Feb, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence concerning organizing F.A.C.T., 1977 (Box 2)
    - Personal notes on organizing F.A.C.T., Circa 1977 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence about F.A.C.T. and Paul Keane, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - F.A.C.T. and other Keane correspondence, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence and other about F.A.C.T., and miscellaneous Keane correspondence, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Donations, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Financial reports, memos, clippings, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Incorporation papers, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Mailing list and related materials, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Newsletter #1, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Newsletter #2, "The Report", 1978 (Box 2)
    - Press releases, Circa 1978 (Box 2)
    - Extra xeroxes, Undated (Box 2)
  - Kent State General Material (Box 2)
    - The A.M ., Kent State Summer News, 1972 June-August (Box 2)
    - Xeroxes of The A.M., 1972 June-August (Box 2)
    - Chuck Takes a Look at KSU, cartoons by Chuck Ayers, Undated (Box 2)
    - Commencement Guide, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Commuter and Off-Campus Newsletter, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Honors and Experimental programs, Undated (Box 2)
    - Honors Day program, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Implosion Pad: memo about experiment in student living, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Kent Alumni Magazine, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Proposals for a "New College", 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Official Kent State Bulletin, 1970 May-June (Box 2)
    - News articles: Glenn Olds, former president, Kent State, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Kent State telephone directories, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Paul Keane
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1980 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, Undated (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2)
      - To and from Kent State, Undated (Box 2)
      - With Kent State archives, Undated (Box 2)
      - James Michener, 1973 (Box 2)
      - Reece Morehead, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
      - Bill Moyers, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
      - Robert Murphy, 1973 (Box 2)
      - Glenn Olds, 1972-1981, 2001, 2005-2009, undated (Box 2)
      - George Urban, Undated (Box 2)
    - Crank mail, Undated (Box 2)
    - F. B. I. file, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Yale Divinity School: notice of memorial service and statement by President Giamatti, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Pop's Snow Squad
      - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
      - Fan mail, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Correspondence regarding snow equipment, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Correspondence with Kent State, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
      - Mailing list, 1973 (Box 3)
      - News articles, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
      - Newsletters, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
      - Publicity, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Receipts, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3)
    - Photographic negatives, Undated (Box 3)
    - Poems found in notes, Undated (Box 3)
    - Copied pages from notebook, 1970-1972 (Box 3)
    - Paper on George Segal's sculpture, with letter by Segal, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Writings by Keane, Undated (Box 3)
    - Vita and recommendations, Undated (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes and printed matter, Undated (Box 3)
    - Notes: Democratic National Convention, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Religious and Community Leaders Concerned (Box 3)
      - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Guidelines for observing demonstration (Miami Beach), 1972 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 3)
      - News articles, 1972 (Box 3)
    - King Alfonso's Unity with Humanity for All, correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Peter Davies
    - Material on Kent State, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: especially relating to donation to Yale, Undated (Box 3)
  - Bill Gordon
    - Correspondence, 1971-1980 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, Undated (Box 3)
    - "Some Cases are Better Left Unopened" by Bill Gordon, Undated (Box 3)
    - Outline of book, possibly by Billl Gordon, Undated (Box 3)
    - Paul Keane criticism of Bill Gordon manuscript, Undated (Box 3)
    - Documents used by Bill Gordon for paper, Undated (Box 3)
    - Kent State: Three Years Later, a Legal Summary, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Review of Kent State Coverup and article on FBI reports – Kent State, 1980 (Box 3)
    - The Kent State Coverup by Bill Gordon, Undated (Box 3)
  - Volume containing issues of For Your Information, Dragonfire, and Stump City, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Daily Kent Stater
    - (bound), 1970 September-1971 June (Box 4)
    - (bound), 1971 September-1972 June (Box 5)
    - (bound), 1972 September-1973 June (Box 6)
    - 26-27 September 1973 (Box 7)
    - 2-12 October 1973 (Box 7)
    - 16-31 October 1973 (Box 7)
    - 1-15 November 1973 (Box 7)
    - 16-29 November 1973 (Box 7)
    - December 1973 (Box 7)
    - 8-15 January 1974 (Box 7)
    - 16-31 January 1974 (Box 7)
    - 1-8 February 1974 (Box 7)
    - 13-28 February 1974 (Box 7)
    - 1-8 March 1974 (Box 7)
    - 12-15 March 1974 (Box 7)
    - 4-16 April 1974 (Box 7)
    - 17-30 April 1974 (Box 7)
    - 1-9 May 1974 (Box 7)
    - 10-30 May 1974 (Box 7)
    - 5-6 June 1974 (Box 7)
    - 4 May 1976 (Box 7)
    - 20-21 October 1977 (Box 7)
    - 20-23 February 1979 (Box 7)
    - 27 February-2 March 1979 (Box 7)
    - 6-9 March 1979 (Box 7)
    - 27-30 March 1979 (Box 7)
    - 3-6 April 1979 (Box 7)
    - 10-13 April 1979 (Box 7)
    - 17-20 April 1979 (Box 7)
    - 24-27 April 1979 (Box 7)
    - 2-4 May 1979 (Box 7)
    - 8-11 May 1979 (Box 7)
    - 15-18 May 1979 (Box 7)
    - 22-25 May 1979 (Box 7)
    - (special issue, Our Times), 24 May 1979 (Box 7)
    - 29 May-1 June 1979 (Box 7)
    - 4-13 September 1979 (Box 7)
    - 14-28 September 1979 (Box 7)
    - 2-12 October 1979 (Box 8)
    - 16-31 October 1979 (Box 8)
    - 1-14 November 1979 (Box 8)
    - 15-30 November 1979 (Box 8)
    - December 1979 (Box 8)
    - January 1980 (Box 8)
    - 1-14 February 1980 (Box 8)
    - 15-29 February 1980 (Box 8)
    - 4-12 March 1980 (Box 8)
    - 13-21 March 1980 (Box 8)
    - 1-11 April 1980 (Box 8)
    - 15-30 April 1980 (Box 8)
    - 1-8 May 1980 (Box 8)
    - 9-16 May 1980 (Box 8)
    - Microfilm, 1972-1974 (Box 8)
    - 27 January- May 15 1981 (Box 8a)
  - News articles
    - From Daily Kent Stater, 1972-1973 (Box 9)
    - From Ohio papers, 1971-1980 (Box 9)
    - From U.S. papers other than Ohio, 1971-1980 (Box 9)
    - Political cartoons, Undated (Box 9)
    - Magazine articles, 1971-1980 (Box 9)
    - Yale Daily News, includes articles on the Kent State Collection at Yale, 1977-1980 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 9)
  - Press releases, 1972-1978 (Box 9)
  - Kent State yearbooks, 1971-1975 (Box 10)
  - James Michener's Kent State, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Poster of Henry Steele Commager's "The University and the Community of Learning", 1971 (Box 11)
- Bill Gordon papers, 1970-1979; Series III
  Researchers must have written permission from Bill Gordon to use his correspondence in Series III, Box 4.
  - Electrostatic copies of FBI records, obtained under the Freedom of Information Act, 1970-1974 (Box 1–2)
  - James A. Michener writings, correspondence, clippings, and Kent State commencement address, Circa 1970-circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - House Judiciary Committee report from Comptroller General on FBI domestic intelligence operations, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Reports and court publications relating to the Kent State shootings, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and clippings relating to the Kent State shootings and aftermath, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    A significant amount of the correspondence is between Paul Keane and Dr. Glenn A. Olds, president of Kent State University.
  - Photographs of Bill Gordon, Paul Keane, Greg Rambo, and Glenn Olds, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bill Gordon correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Researchers must have written permission from Bill Gordon to use his correspondence in Series III, box 4.
  - Barry Levine article in The Spectrum, 1971 November 10 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Jerry M. Lewis research reports, Circa 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Dr. Robert I. White press conference, transcript, 1970 May 5 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Supreme Court arguments, 1973 December (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - John P. Adams article for Cleveland State Law Review (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Garry Trudeau, Doonesbury, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Everybody v. Kleindienst briefs, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Logos radio program with Paul Keane, Greg Rambo, Jerry Lewis, Carl Moore, and Lew Fried, moderator, transcript, 1971 November (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Nationwide petition drive, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Profile of Paul Keane, draft and notes, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Audio recordings
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    Copies of commercially produced audiovisual materials contained in this collection cannot be made for researcher use outside of the repository.
    - Statement issued by Kent State shooting parents and others, 1974 March 31; 1 audiotape (Reel-to-reel) (Box 6)
    - "Struggle for Justice," Bill Moyers, 1974 January 16; 1 commercially produced audiocassette (Box 7)
    - Recording of news programs regarding Kent State shootings, 1973; 1 commercially produced audiocassette (Box 8)
      Includes "Morning Exchange" (1973 Sep 17); NBC News (1973 Sep 20); NBC "Scene on Sunday" (1973 Sep 23); and Harry Reasoner report on "Week in Review" (1973 Sep 23).
    - Bill Moyers Journal, "Justice Delayed," and Walter Cronkite Show/Charles Kuralt, 1972 December 19, 22; 1 commercially produced audiocassette (Box 9)
- James Munves papers, 1970-1981; Series IV
  See also Accession 1987-M-096.
  - Interviews
    - John Adams, Board of Church & Soc., United Methodist Ch. (Box 1)
    - Burton Ascheim, friend of Allison Krause's sister, who overheard Judge Young in elevator during Kr. V. Rh. (Box 1)
    - Alan and Albert Canfora: Alan was one of 9 wounded students; Albert is his father (Box 1)
    - Ramsey Clark, slated to serve as chief trial counsel for plaintiffs in Kr v Rh until he withdrew from case (Box 1)
    - John Cleary, one of the 9 wounded students (Box 1)
    - Peter Davies, associated with Krause & Adams in effort to obtain federal grand jury, author of K. A. Challenge to the Amer. Conscience (Box 1)
    - Paul Donner, civil libertarian, file contains articles on spying at KSU (Box 1)
    - David Engdahl, attorney associated with Steven Sindell and later representing Krause in Kr v Rh; law professor at Univ of Colorado, student of martial law, etc. (Box 1)
    - Marcus Friedman, Dayton attorney who knew Judge Don Young when he was an attorney (Box 1)
    - Burt Fulton, chief counsel for defendants in Kr v Rh (with C. Brown) (Box 1)
    - Michael Geltner, ACLU attorney in Kr v Rh (Box 1)
    - Thomas Grace and parents; Tom was one of 9 wounded students (Box 1)
    - Fred Hogle, Ravenna att'y, took part in defense of "Kent 25" indicted by special grand jury (Box 1)
    - Dean Kahler and parents; Dean was one of the 9 wounded students (Box 1)
    - Nelson Karl, Cleveland ACLU att'y in Kr v Rh (2 folders labelled) (Box 1)
    - Joseph Kelner, NYC trial lawyer, co-author of The Kent State Coverup, chief counsel for plaintiffs in Kr v Oh 1st trial, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Robert Kelner, NYC trial lawyer, son of Joseph, counsel in Kr v Rh, 1st trial (Box 1)
    - Arthur Krause, father of Allison Krause, killed at KSU (Box 1)
    - Prof. Jerry Lewis, KSU Sociology Dept., present at shootings; wrote papers on shootings (Box 1)
    - Joseph Lewis, Galen Keller: Lewis was one of 9 wounded students, Galen Keller was a para-legal for plaintiffs in Kr v Rh (Box 1)
    - Mrs. Lewis, mother of Joseph (Box 1)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Louis Schroeder, parents of Wm Schroeder, killed at KSU (Box 1)
    - Schroeder interview (belongs with previous interview, this folder had been received in an earlier accession) (Box 1)
    - Donald Scott Mackenzie, one of the 9 wounded students (Box 1)
    - Fred Mandel, Cleveland att'y, counsel for plaintiffs in Kr v Rh, 1st trial (Box 1)
    - Bernard Mazel, direct mail expert who solicited funds for plaintiffs in Kr v Rh; it contains newspaper advertisement and direct mail pieces, as well as program of Artists for Justice benefit. (Box 1)
    - Mrs. Elaine Holstein, mother of Jeffrey Miller (Box 1)
    - Sanford Rosen, ACLU att'y, handled appeal in Kr v Rh to 6th circuit and became chief counself for plaintiffs in 2nd trial (Box 1)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Martin Scheuer, parents of Sandy Scheuer, killed at KSU (Box 1)
    - David Scribner, NYC att'y, master-minded defense of 'Kent State 25' and won suit to have spec. grand jury report expunged (Box 1)
    - Robert Stamps and parents; Stamps was one of the 9 wounded students (Box 1)
    - Benson Wolman, head of Ohio branch of ACLU (Box 1)
    - Doug Wrentmore, Jan Wrentmore; Doug was one of the 9 wounded students; Jan is his mother (Box 1)
  - Legal
    - Cases under 1983, civil section of fed civil rts act (Box 1)
    - Cases under 242, criminal section of fed civil rts act (Box 1)
    - Complaints in Kr v Rh, these are documents that started civil law suit (Box 1)
    - Criminal trial, federal US v Shafer (Box 1)
    - Depositions taken in connection with civil suit (Kr v Rh) summary of (Box 1)
    - Federal grand jury (Box 1)